hello ladies and gentlemen and welcome
同学们 大家好 欢迎你们
my name is Walker Stipe and I'm with the
我是沃克老师
Palo Alto education today
来自Palo Alto教育 今天
we will be discussing some very exciting science stuff
我们将会一起讨论非常有趣的话题
what exactly would be discussing
究竟今天要讨论什么呢
well first let's start with a question
首先先问你们一个问题
am i happy today
今天我高兴吗
hmm maybe I am maybe I'm not
可能高兴 可能不高兴
maybe I'm having a bummer of a day that's okay
可能今天有件事情让我很生气
but can you tell just by
但是你能够通过观察我
looking at me and the way I'm talking
或者是观察我说话的方式之类的
and stuff like that if I'm happy
知道我开心与否吗
perhaps you can perhaps you can not
可能你可以 可能不行
in either case we have a fun project ahead of us
不管怎么样 我们今天都有一个非常有趣的任务
ladies and gentlemen we are going to
各位同学们
teach a computer to determine whether or
今天我们要教计算机
not someone is happy amazing
判断一个人是否开心 酷啊
how can this be done this sounds too difficult
这听起来也太难了 怎么做到的
I could never do such a things
我永远都做不到的
Oh contraire you're gonna do it
恰恰相反 你可以做到的
we're gonna do it we got this
我们都会做到的 没问题的
so we're gonna hop in do a little smash into the keyboard
我们只要进入程序 敲敲键盘
a little bit of coding up some stuff
做点代码编程
we're gonna
我们就可以做到
make a computer that can recognize
我们可以教会计算机
whether or not someone is happy or not
识别一个人是否开心
so let's hop in
让我们开始吧
already we are hopping in
第一件事
first thing we want to do so want to go to this website
我们要去这样一个网站
as you can see the URL is at the top
正如你在屏幕上方看到的
you can copy this exactly as it is into your web browser
你可以把网址直接复制到浏览器
or you can just go to machinelearningforkids
或者直接搜索 machinelearningforkids
just type that into Google the first thing
直接谷歌搜索就可以 第一个链接就是
then what you want to do is we go to worksheets
然后我们要去工作区
just where we are now
就是我们现在在的地方
you want to get this little guy right here
下载这个文件
or downloadthe  project worksheet kids is our
选择下载project worksheet(工程工作表)
step by step how to get to our goal
它能一步步带领我们实现目标
so that is what I have done and when I do
这就是我们需要做的 然后
that we get to this which is a wonderful guide
我们就会得到这个超级棒的任务指南
to the project we are going to create
它将指导我们接下来的任务
so as we see this is kind of what
正如我们所看到的
our finished product will look like
这就是我们成品的样子
my art if you can believe
这是一件艺术品
it is it's not it's not great
也不算是一件艺术品
you'll see it in the moment it's not
你很快就能亲眼见证
I'm not going to school to be an artist let's just say that
我不会去学校做一个美术课老师 我开玩笑的
so now we're here we have this file
所以我们现在有这个文件了
we're looking at it what's next
下一步要做什么呢
well we want to get ready we want to login
我们要登陆网站
If you don't have log in
如果你登陆出现了问题
I'm sure your teacher can help you
你的老师可以帮助你
so now you're logged in what do we do
所以现在我们已经登陆了 我们要做什么
now well as we see we click on projects
点击项目这个选项
where is projects projects is right
项目就在这里
there so you go to that guy and then
点击它 然后
make a new project
我们要创建一个新项目
it's your project boom done what do we want
这是你的项目 好啦完成
to name this project well
给它取什么名字
what we're doing is we're trying to make
我们正努力教会计算机
our computer happy trying to determine
识别一个人是否开心
these things so you can name it make me happy
所以我们可以叫它 让我开心
that's what I did
像我一样
what is it recognizing
所以计算机究竟要识别什么
what's it trying to learn
计算机要学习什么
well it's trying to learn text make a letters
计算机要学习打字
for instance words we're talking to it right
这就是我们接下来要做的
so we do that and then create boom
我们有了项目
so now we should see that we have the
页面上已经有我们的项目了
make me happy project exists now it's empty
但是 它里面空空如也
we ddin't do anything else
我们现在什么都没做呢
so here's we change that a lot
这是我们做完之后得到样子
we have that now
它变了许多
what are these for these what are these
我们接下来究竟
next three steps do we want to to follow
要遵循哪三个步骤呢
well of course we want to go to scratch
首先我们肯定要进入脚本
because we're making it from scratch
因为我们是从零开始做的
so click the scratch next little box will
点击进入脚本
come up and you will click the scratch by itself
然后脚本窗口会弹出
but to get to this screen right here now
但是要做成这个样子
with the magic of video editing
多亏了视频剪辑
I already have done this part
我已经做好了
now I guarantee you it's rather simple
我向你保证这很简单
for all the different little guys you need
小编程家 你们需要
click on these they're color coded all
点击这些不同的颜色的区域
admit that helps me a whole lot and
我们必须承认它们用处很大
in our healthy little guide right here
在我们的小指南里面有一个艺术品
it has artwork make your own artwork
你也可以做
have some fun with that why not right
玩的开心就好
actually this is something that I would
实际上我要强烈推荐你们
highly recommend is the duplicate function
这个复制功能
all right so we have our photo
我们有图片
dude right but how do i duplicate it is
但是如何复制它呢
is there a duplicate button No
有没有复制按钮 并没有
so on your mouse this guy
我们要用到鼠标
you want to look at this guy right here
然后我们的对象是这幅图片
and click the right mouse key oh who is this
点击鼠标右键 哇 这是什么
this is your duplicate friend boom
这是复制功能呀
you're welcome there you go all right
不用感谢我
so you're gonna do that and you can make three
然后你要做的就是复制三份
copies and then you're gonna add some smile
然后加上 微笑
have some funs
随便你加
let's peruse mine shall we
让我们好好看看我的作品
yeah well we'll get to that all right
我们等会儿再来看 好吧
so this is what we want to create so I have done so
这是我们要达到的效果 我已经做了
it can be done I guarantee
我保证能做出来的
it's just this and they're all just
很简单 只需要你
drag-and-drop and sometimes
拖——放——   拖——放——
you got a finite little bit wiggle all around
然后再做出一些细微的调整就可以了
it'll pop in so once we have done so
做完了这一步之后
we move on to saving it
请保存文件
you know we're gonna hold these
我们要保存
changes we've made so we do that
做出的一些调整
and now what we can do we can run it
我们现在就可以运行它了
so what we can do here is type things
我们在这里打字
we can type things what things shall we
打什么内容呢
type well we have trained our little
我们已经训练了机器
little guy to look to be happy when
当别人说你真棒的时候
someone says I think you're awesome
做出开心的表情
and that alone if I say I think you're the
最好不要说 “你是世界上最好的人”
best ever you've never heard of that before
因为它没听过
so let's talk to our computer
让我们试着和电脑交谈吧
let's talk to our computer it sounds a
和电脑交谈
little weird but we're gonna do it
听起来有点怪异，但这正是我们要做的
so we're gonna say I think you're awesome
我们说 我觉得你非常棒
and makes the computer so happy
电脑非常开心
look at that artwork oh my oh my goodness
快看这件艺术品 我的天哪
I know I'm a Picasso or one of those guys
我知道我是毕加索之类的画家
so I'd say I think you're the best ever
现在我要说  我觉得你是最最好的
excellent three exclamation marks
再加三个感叹号
well he doesn't know what to do with that
他不知道该怎么做
he's never he's never heardthese things before
因为他从来没有听过这些话
we're gonna learn how to do better than this
我们马上就能改善这个缺点
so this is a way that we can't do things
毕竟这样子行不通
you don't tell them exactly look for this
我们不能只说他们知道的词
if someone says I think you're awesome
如果有人说我认为你太棒了
then they'll get excited
它会兴奋
but if I think you're great wonderful stupendous superb
但如果改成我认为你 贼棒 特别棒 棒呆了
I don't know what that means
他就不知道该如何反应了
so let's move on alrighty so we can see this now
所以我们要继续学习
you can move on from that window
可以往下移了
the next step we're gonna train
下一步我们要训练计算机
train our little dude to do better
让它做的更好
we're gonna train him to do better
要训​​练它做得更好
so we're gonna press the train button hop on that train
点击训练按钮（train）然后进入页面
then we're gonna create a dataset
然后我们要创建一个数据集
ooh dataset who's so fancy
这花哨的名字是个什么东西
what adataset is it's stuff in this instance
数据集 在这个例子中
it is things that you would hear
就是你听到之后
that would make you happy or sad
会变得开心或者难过的话的集合
and we will place them in two boxes
我们把它们 分别装在两个集合里
boxes I like hearing that
比如说我喜欢的话
that brightens my day
应该能照亮我的一天
and sad ouch that might be true maybe I got to work on
让我难过的话 可能是指出我的毛病
that wasn't something that made me feel very warm inside
并不让我觉得温暖
so the kind things surprise put the kind things
所以我们把好的话放在这个集合里
and the mean things to put are those things
把那些尖酸刻薄的话 比如让我生气的话
that are just well a bit of a bummer
放入这个集合里
all right so we do that and this is important
还有一件非常重要的事情
this is important I ran up against this mild erro
我犯过这个小错误
make sure you have at least 10 in each box
请确保每个集合里至少有10句话
because if you have less
如果少了的话
well it it won't work
程序就会出错
you'll be like you need more
你需要更多的句子
and so I'll just tell you right at front you need at least ten
每个集合至少需要10句话
they're gonna be short words that's what I did
你也可以加一些短词 我就是这么做的
cool nice hard-working that's two words
酷 好 认真 认真有两个字了
but you get the gist to do that
反正你知道我的意思
and then hit the learn and test button
然后点击 学习&测试 按钮
which I believe looks like this one
它长这个样子
it looks like this wants to press that one
然后你点击这个按钮
and it should go to a page read wait a little bit
它会跳到一个界面 上面写着请稍等
you're like is anything happening
发生了什么
yes yes it is amazing machine learning
是的 机器正在学习
things are happening at IBM Watson ooh
就像IMB的电脑 沃森在学习一样
that scientists things
让科学界为之振奋
next thing you know you have your trained model
之后你就可以得到你的训练模型了
and this is where the really cool stuff starts happening
在这里 真正酷炫的事情即将发生
so we do that and all of a sudden
我们这样做后 忽然
we have this thing all of a sudden
我们就有了模型 忽然之间
we can talk to our computer
我们就可以以一种更智能的方式
in a much more intelligent way
和我们的电脑交谈了
so we're gonna go back for a project
所以我们回到项目
and we're gonna skip over some of the stuff here
我们要跳过一些东西
but that's what you're gonna do
但是你要做
but it's just simple
它很简单
follow the steps
照做就好
you've already made the code segment here
这里你已经做好了代码
you have already made a code segment
你已经创建好了代码
now you're going to change this code stuff
现在你要把这些代码
here into this stuff right here
变成这个样子
now I just kept this around because
我把这个先放在这里
this is something that I didn't really notice
有些东西我可能没调整
we needed to change until I was having some odd issues
所以先把它放在这
so this is an if-else statement
这是一个if else语句
if there's chocolate sauce
如果有巧克力酱
I will put it on my ice cream
我会把它加在我的冰淇淋上
if there's chocolate sauce
如果有巧克力酱
then I'll put it on my ice cream
然后我会把它加在我的冰淇淋上
otherwise I'll have a brownie
不然我就会吃一个布朗尼
sure but these are different
当然他们不太一样
basically this is if then if then
这个是如果 然后 如果 然后
this is if else this is one thing
这个是如果 不然 这是一件事
so just note that make sure you don't mix that as I did
注意 不要像我一样混淆它们
alright so and then I believe we get so from more blocks
好的 然后我们打开“more blocks”
we get this is basically
这里是机器学习
what we just made with all our machine learning
利用我们之前的数据库
from our training data set that we made
所产生的
so we put that in here and then
我们把这个放到这里来
this is where the amazing things happen
神奇的事就要发生了
let's say let's recall it over here we said
我记得我们之间说的是
exactly I think you're awesome
你真的很棒
well do we still think does
现在这句话能不能
that still like me feel good well yes
让计算机开心呢 可以
it does okay good nice
可以 很好
and I start what about you are great
让我们输入 “你简直伟大” 试试看
well it didn't work now that's interesting
不行 这很有趣
what about just great
那如果只是输入 “伟大”
maybe it caught on my my bad spelling
或许我刚刚拼写有误
if you caught that
可能你也发现了
now it's an important note
友情提醒
okay you think oh we're using machine learning
你可能觉得 我们在用机器学习
it's got science it's foolproof
很科学 它万无一失
it's amazing look at it goes
看起来很神奇
it's perfect
简直完美
actually this is probably the one area of science
这可能是科学无法声称
that makes no claim on being perfect
自己完美的一个领域
you know he's the popular kid
比如说他是一个受人欢迎的人
he's the fastest guy on the track team
田径队里他跑的最快
he's shooting rooting those straight A's and
他可能每门课都得A
yet he's not perfect he makes mistakes
但是他也并不完美 他也会犯错
you know he's not seen everything
他不是所以东西都见过
he's only seen ten compliments
他只见过10句赞美的话
he's been told he's wonderful in ten ways
人们只用10种方式夸奖过他
and not sogreat in ten other ways
还有10种方式批评他
well apparently your great misspelled
很明显 你把伟大拼错了
for in his mind made him feel bad
这让他感觉不太好
maybe he just really likes spelling
因为他可能喜欢拼写
but if we just say great as we showed a moment ago
但是如果我们正确拼写的话
well that just makes his day
他会很开心
so what things can we say
我们还可以说什么
so cool makes him feel great
如此酷 这让他感觉很棒
and you can try a bunch of things
你可以多多尝试
and for the most part it should work
大部分情况下 应该它都是有反应的
it's not gonna work perfectly
它不会一点错都不出
don't don't expect that and
不要指望它完全不犯错误
that's okay that's machine learning
犯错没关系 这就是机器学习
in general it is non-deterministic
一般来说 它是非确定性的
is the fancy word for that
这是花哨一点的表达
all right so let's see how it does on
好的，让我们看看它对于不好的评价
the not-so-great things
是如何反应的
well let's say you are just so tired today
输入 你今天太累了
he's tired it's okay to be tired you know you need sleep
他很累 不过很正常 所以我们才需要睡眠
and sometimes you just don't get enough
有时候你没办法得到充足的睡眠
it's good to try to get that
尝试多睡挺好
but sometimes it just can't
但是有时候你没时间睡觉
what about hungry just labeling things
输入饿的话会怎么样呢
I am a little bit right now
我现在的确有点饿
mm-hmm-hmm what about nasty
输入令人讨厌的呢
let's just say he got to take a shower
比如说他忘记洗澡了
forgot to brush his teeth just one of those days
忘记刷牙了
so we see on the whole
我们可以看到 总的来说
it has learned other things than
除了我们告诉它的东西之外
just exactly what we told it to memorize
他已经学会对其他东西反应
that kind of makes sense
这是可行的
it's the difference between understanding
他们的区别就好像理解
and Iliterally just memorized what was on the
和机械记住考试内容
test or what my friends like exactly
或者我朋友喜欢什么
and then if there's anything a little bit
如果有一些有点不一样的
different they don't know what it is
他们不知道的事情
so that is what we are going on here
所以这就是我们要继续做下去的事情
all right Walker I've heard I've heard you
好了我们已经讲完了
about we've run through the programming
并且也自己亲身经历一番了
we got it to work
我们让计算机运行了
maybe we didn't that's okay
失败也没有关系
that's okay happiness sadness that's it
只有幸福和悲伤这两种表情嘛
what about you know look at Darth Vader
看看达斯维达
look at his face look at it he's feeling
看着他的脸
he's feeling so much so much more than
他的表情可远比
just happy and sad life is so much more
快乐和悲伤来的多
exciting than just happy and sad
生活里面的情绪也远远比快乐悲伤要多
when you've only mentioned happy and sad
当你只提到快乐和悲伤
what's up with that come on that's just
其他情绪怎么办 这样不行
wrong you're right it is wrong
没错 这样不行
it's too simple but it's something we can do
它太简单了 但是在有限时间的课程内
in a short little video
我们也只能先学习简单的了
so there's that for you
先消化今天的内容吧
so moving on what's what's the next step
所以下一步我们可以怎么做呢
what are some things that we could try and do
我们可以尝试什么
we could try and recognize well
我们可以尝试让计算机识别
are they are they angry how angry are they
他们生气吗 他们又是有多生气
are they angry and sad
他们既悲伤又生气吗
so this is actually very much an open research question
这其实是个开放性的问题
which is another way of saying
换一种说法
it's really difficult like really difficult
它真的很难 真的真的很难
and the kind of fun part about it
而它有趣的部分就在于
and this is most machine learning projects
大多数机器学习也是一样
are they're never 100 percent right
它们不会百分之百正确
they're never like
它们不会说
oh this is a fact this is a hundred percent true
这绝对是事实 它绝对正确
no one can disagree
大家都认为如此
cuz think about emotions you know
不信想想情绪
you think about yourself right
想想你自己
now how are you feeling
你现在感觉怎么样
you might feel pretty good or a pretty bad
你感觉还不错 或者感觉不好
but if you were to try to give a number to that
你要为你的情绪打个分
I'm feeling like nine point nine out of ten awesome right now
我现在的好心情有9.9分 满分10分的话
but exactly nine point nine
但是真的正好是9.9吗
what if it is nine point nine nine
有没有可能是9.99
what if it's nine point nine o
有没有可能是9.90
well gets a little silly
有点傻
and to ever really definitively say
通常说  这是解决问题唯一的方法
this is the only way might not ever happen
是不可能的
but that's okay in this field
但是在这里是可以的
in this machinelearning stuff
在机器学习这个领域是可以的
because if you can get close
因为你已经很靠近正确答案了
you know they're mad you know
你知道他们生气了
just kind of like say that and you guess
你已经猜到
they just get acrossed
他们生气了
you know we should be a little careful around this person
所以你知道和他相处的时候得小心一点
because they're having an extremely bad day
因为他今天的心情非常糟糕
or this person is having an awesome day
或者他今天心情超好
I'm gonna hang around with them
那我就会和他玩
because I would also like to have an awesome day
因为我也想要度过开心的一天
so that's kind of a fun of machine learning
这就是机器学习的乐趣